Hello friends, welcome to Tippon Sites.
In today's video, we will talk
about maternity care cover. Does your
health insurance policy cover maternity care, that is, does it
cover delivery?
Many people have this question in their mind.
They do not know whether their
policy has maternity cover or not, whether the
delivery process is covered or not.
So, we are going to discuss that in this video. So, please
like the video
and watch the video till the end and
subscribe to the channel. So let's start the video
[Music]. There are
two types of health insurance policies. One is an
individual policy and the other is a
corporate policy.
I have made a particular video for you about both the policies,
you can watch it, but
I am going to tell you a little about both of them
so that you get to know about maternity cover. So,
first let us talk about
individual policy. An individual policy is a
policy taken by you by
choosing a plan of your choice and we have
purchased that policy; it is an individual policy,
so what happens in it is that whatever
individual  There is a policy that does
not cover maternity.
We have to take a separate plan for maternity care, an additional
plan within our policy.
Many companies have
started selling maternity plans these days. It was not available before,
but now it has started coming.
Maternity plans are now available within individual policies and
many people have started taking them.
One thing we have to keep in mind is that there is
a limit for maternity,
both in individual policies and in corporate policies. So,
how much limit should we take and how much is covered
under our plan, we have to check that thing in
advance. If the hospital
bill exceeds that limit, then
we may have to make some payment at that time.
Otherwise, if our bill is within that limit, then
we do not have to make any payment.
This is within the individual policy
and is different for the corporate policy.
Mostly,
maternity is covered under the corporate policy and it also has a limit. So,
we should already know
what is the limit of our maternity care.  If we know that in advance,
we can get our treatment done for free
and by going to the hospital,
we can find out in advance the rates of delivery or maternity care
or its package, only
after that we
can get our treatment done, so
we should know these things in advance that
what is the limit related to our maternity in our policy, there are two
types of limits, one is for normal
delivery and the other is for caesarean delivery,
so the limits of both are different,
so we should know the limits of both,
under the corporate policy, if a
candidate does not know or his employee does
not know, then he should talk to his HR,
in the company where he works, there is
an HR team, in that HR team,
a particular person
looks after the entire work related to health insurance, he himself looks after the entire
process of the entire policy, so
you can also call him and
find out the limit of your maternity,
you will also get to know from these two things.  If you are
unable to find out whether your policy has
maternity cover or not, then you can contact your
insurance company by calling their customer care number
or their website, or from
whomever
you have purchased the policy or from an agent
or from any online portal or from Policy
Bazaar etc., then you can
contact them and find out about your policy whether it has
maternity cover
or not. So that's all for today's video. If you liked the
video, then like it and
subscribe to the channel. See you
in the next video. Till then,
hello.